<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fantasy on voithos.io</title>
    <link>https://voithos.io/tags/fantasy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fantasy on voithos.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://voithos.io/tags/fantasy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Messenger</title>
      <link>https://voithos.io/writing/the-messenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://voithos.io/writing/the-messenger/</guid>
      <description>Emerick Reeve stood, arms crossed, near the entrance of the open-air bazaar. The merchant, a quivering, balding man in his forties, stared at him intently, a film of sweat glistening on his forehead.&#xA;“Tell me again, what was your price for the horse?” he said, unmoving. The merchant hesitated, eyed him up and down before briefly glancing at the woman standing nearby. She had a pouch of coin in hand, and was about to hand it all over before Emerick intervened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call of the Giant</title>
      <link>https://voithos.io/writing/the-call-of-the-giant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://voithos.io/writing/the-call-of-the-giant/</guid>
      <description>“Home is north.”&#xA;Ketil froze as the words materialized in his mind. They were hushed, easy to miss, but they had been coming regularly enough now that he had learned to pick them out. For months, he had been enduring these whispers and the pull they exerted on him. He could feel it: a draw, a kind of primal longing, no doubt from whatever was the source of the words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amidst the Sands of the Silent Sea</title>
      <link>https://voithos.io/writing/amidst-the-sands-of-the-silent-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://voithos.io/writing/amidst-the-sands-of-the-silent-sea/</guid>
      <description>I remember how that time began.&#xA;First, I saw light, as my mind coalesced from the void. The blurred lights in front of me solidified as my mind’s eye emerged, small, young, yet aware. An endless landscape spread out before me, reaching toward the horizon. I shifted my view without moving and beheld the world.&#xA;The sky was crimson red, glowing with a flame that marked the day’s passing. The radiance was rivaled only by the uncaring sands and rocks of the barren land below me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
